Guide to the Sweetheart of Texas Concert Hall and Saloon poster collection, 1974-1975 MS 662
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Sweetheart of Texas Concert Hall and Saloon poster collection
1974-1975
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Bryant, Bruce
MS 662
2.25 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
0.0423 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0662aip_001 (0.0423 GB)
This collection mainly contains posters from the Sweetheart of Texas Concert Hall and Saloon.
Biographical / Historical
Dee Brown, Bruce Bryant, and Charlie Hargrave opened the Sweetheart of Texas Concert Hall and Saloon in December 1974. It closed in the fall of 1975. The Houston venue located at 120 Milam in the Buffalo Bayou Fleamart hosted a variety of acts including Don Sanders, Ramblin' Jack Elliott, Dogtooth Violet, Eric Taylor, Lucinda Williams, among others.
Scope and Contents
This collection mainly contains posters from the Sweetheart of Texas Concert Hall and Saloon, as well as other related venues.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Bruce Bryant in August 2016.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
African Americans; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Folk music; Folk-rock music; Music; Women
Subjects (Persons)
Sanders, Don; Van Zandt, Townes
Subjects (Corporations)
Wheatfield
- Series I: Sweetheart of Texas posters
  - Dogtooth Violet, 1974-12-06-1974-12-07 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Performers include: Dogtooth Violet, Vince Bell and Friends, Captain Macho, Bill and Lucille cade with Pete Gorisch.
  - Denim, 1974-12-26-1974-12-28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New Year's Eve Party, 1974-12-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Dogtooth Violet, George Ensle, The Cypress Swamp Stompers, and Fredrique and His French Guillotine
  - Clifton Chenier, 1975-01-24-1975-02-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Clifton Chenier, Dogtooth Violet, Kenneth Threadgill, Denim
  - Greazy Wheels (2 copies one with performers written in red ink), 1975-02-20-1975-03-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers included: Greazy Wheels, Townes Van Zandt, Ramblin' Jack Elliott, Steve Fromholz
  - Alex Harvey, 1975-05-01-1975-05-17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Alex Harvey, Dogtooth Violet, Townes Van Zandt, and Bill Staines
  - Ray Wylie Hubbard, 1975-05-29-1975-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - May 1975 Calendar (reprint), 1975-05-02-1975-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Ramblin' Jack Elliott, Lucinda Williams, Dogtooth Violet, Cypress Swamp Stompers, Ray Wylie Hubbard and The Cowboy Twinkies, Augie Meyers and The Western Head Band, Townes Van Zandt, Hemmer Ridge Mountain Boys, Richard Dobson, David Rodriguez, Rocky Hill, Kenneth Threadgill and The Velvet Cow Pasture Band, Bill and Lucille Cade, Stephen Jarrard, Peter Gorisch, Clifton Chenier, John Vandiver, Wheatfield, Don Sanders, Bill Staines, Steve Fromholz, Vince Bell, Eric Taylor, Denim, Hickory, Willis Alan Ramsey, Greezy Wheels, George Ensle, and Bill Haymes
  - Don Sanders, 1975-06-06 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Don Sanders, Lucinda Williams], Sandy Lee, Uncle Sam, and Bobby G.
  - Hickory, 1975-06-13-1975-06-14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Steve Fromholz, 1975-06-20-1975-06-21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Greezy Wheels, 1975-07-24-1975-07-26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ramblin' Jack Elliott (signed), 1975-08-08-1975-08-09 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Denim, 1975-08-15-1975-08-16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Muscular Dystrophy Benefit, 1975-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Dogtooth Violet
  - Reunion (2), 1982-03-21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Performers include: Dogtooth Violet and John Vandiver
- Series II: Memorabilia
  - Navy T-shirt, ca. 1975 (Box 1)
  - Tan Reunion T-shirt, 1982-03-21 (Box 1)
  - Blue T-shirt, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Wooden folding chair, pre-1970s
    An example of audience chair at the music venue. One of 150 bought in bulk by the owners from a nearby downtown seafood restaurant.
- Series III: General files
  - Business records, 1974-1975, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera, 1974, 1975, ca. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Musician contracts, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Audio
  - R.W. Crouch and The Bum Steers - "Sweetheart of Texas", 1975
    There is a master wav file and an access copy mp3.